And how do we do it? We first and foremost find young, passionate, educated youth from the same villages. Both men and women. And we call them Team Balika, balika just means the girl child, so this is a team that we are creating for the girl child. And so once we recruit our community volunteers, we train them, we mentor them, we hand-hold them. That's when our work starts. And the first piece we do is about identifying every single girl who's not going to school. But the way we do it is a little different and high-tech, at least in my view. Each of our frontline staff have a smartphone. It has its own Educate Girls app. And this app has everything that our team needs. It has digital maps of where they're going to be conducting the survey, it has the survey in it, all the questions, little guides on how best to conduct the survey, so that the data that comes to us is in real time and is of good quality. So armed with this, our teams and our volunteers go door-to-door to every single household to find every single girl who may either we never enrolled or dropped out of school. And because we have this data and technology piece, very quickly we can figure out who the girls are and where they are. Because each of our villages are geotagged, and we can actually build that information out very, very quickly. And so once we know where the girls are, we actually start the process of bringing them back into school. And that actually is just our community mobilization process, it starts with village meetings, neighborhood meetings, and as you see, individual counseling of parents and families, to be able to bring the girls back into school. And this can take anything from a few weeks to a few months. And once we bring the girls into the school system, we also work with the schools to make sure that schools have all the basic infrastructure so that the girls will be able to stay. And this would include a separate toilet for girls, drinking water, things that will help them to be retained. But all of this would be useless if our children weren't learning. So we actually run a learning program. And this is a supplementary learning program, and it's very, very important, because most of our children are first-generation learners. That means there's nobody at home to help them with homework, there's nobody who can support their education. Their parents can't read and write. So it's really, really key that we do the support of the learning in the classrooms. So this is essentially our model, in terms of finding, bringing the girls in, making sure that they're staying and learning. And we know that our model works. And we know this because a most recent randomized control evaluation confirms its efficacy. Our evaluator found that over a three-year period Educate Girls was able to bring back 92 percent of all out-of-school girls back into school. (Applause) And in terms of learning, our children's learning went up significantly as compared to control schools. So much so, that it was like an additional year of schooling for the average student.
¿Cómo lo hacemos? Ante todo, buscamos a jóvenes entusiastas, comprometidos y educados de esos mismos pueblos. Hombres y mujeres. Los llamamos "equipo Balika" –balika significa "la niña"–. Es un equipo que creamos para las niñas. Y una vez que hemos reclutado nuestro grupo de voluntarios locales, los entrenamos, les enseñamos y los guiamos. Así empieza nuestro trabajo. Y lo primero que hacemos es identificar a cada una de las niñas que no va a la escuela en ese lugar. Pero lo hacemos de un modo diferente y con alta tecnología, por lo menos desde mi punto de vista. Cada miembro del personal tiene un teléfono inteligente, con la aplicación "Educate Girls". Y esta aplicación tiene todo lo que nuestro equipo necesita. Tiene mapas digitales de los lugares donde realizarán las encuestas, la encuesta misma, todas las preguntas, y pequeñas guías de cómo realizarla mejor, de modo que los datos nos llegan en tiempo real y son de buena calidad. Armados con esto, nuestros equipos y voluntarios van de puerta en puerta a cada hogar, para encontrar a cada una de las niñas que quizá nunca fueron inscriptas o abandonaron la escuela. Y, como tenemos estos datos y esta tecnología, podemos saber muy rápidamente quiénes son las niñas y dónde están. Porque cada uno de los pueblos están geolocalizados y entonces podemos construir esa información muy rápidamente. Una vez que sabemos dónde están las niñas podemos empezar el proceso de traerlas de vuelta a la escuela. Y este es nuestro proceso de movilización comunitaria: empieza con reuniones en el pueblo, reuniones con el vecindario y, como ven, asesoramiento individual a los padres y las familias para poder lograr que las niñas vuelvan a la escuela. Esto puede llevar desde unas pocas semanas hasta varios meses. Cuando las niñas ya regresaron al sistema escolar, trabajamos con las escuelas para asegurarnos de que estas tengan la infraestructura básica para que las niñas puedan quedarse. Esto incluye un baño separado para las niñas, agua potable, las cosas que ayuden a que no se vayan. Pero todo esto sería inútil si nuestros niños no aprenden. Por lo que llevamos a cabo un programa de aprendizaje, que es suplementario, y es muy, muy importante, ya que la mayoría de nuestros niños son estudiantes de primera generación. Eso significa que nadie los puede ayudar en casa con la tarea, no hay nadie que pueda apoyar su educación. Sus padres no saben leer ni escribir. Por lo que realmente es clave que realicemos el apoyo escolar en las aulas. Así que, este es nuestro modelo, en cuanto a encontrar a las niñas, traerlas y asegurarnos de que se queden y aprendan. Sabemos que nuestro modelo funciona. Y lo sabemos porque una reciente evaluación de control aleatorizada confirma su eficiencia. Nuestro evaluador encontró que en un período de tres años 'Educate Girls' pudo hacer regresar a la escuela el 92 % de todas las niñas que estaban excluidas. (Aplausos) Y, en términos de aprendizaje, nuestros niños se superaron de modo significativo en comparación con otras escuelas de control. Esto fue como un año adicional de escolarización para el alumno promedio.
And that's enormous, when you think about a tribal child who's entering the school system for the first time. So here we have a model that works; we know it's scalable, because we are already functioning at 13,000 villages. We know it's smart, because of the use of data and technology. We know that it's sustainable and systemic, because we work in partnership with the community, it's actually led by the community. And we work in partnership with the government, so there's no creation of a parallel delivery system. And so because we have this innovative partnership with the community, the government, this smart model, we have this big, audacious dream today. And that is to solve a full 40 percent of the problem of out-of-school girls in India in the next five years. (Applause) And you're thinking, that's a little ...
Y esto es enorme, si piensan en un niño de una tribu que ingresa al sistema escolar por primera vez. Así que tenemos un modelo que funciona; sabemos que es escalable, porque ya se está llevando a cabo en 13 000 pueblos. Sabemos que es inteligente, porque emplea datos y tecnología. Sabemos que es sostenible y sistémico, porque trabajamos en asociación con la comunidad, en realidad, lo lleva a cabo la comunidad. Y trabajamos en asociación con el gobierno, por lo que no se crea un sistema paralelo de entrega. Y como tenemos esta asociación innovadora con la comunidad y con el gobierno, y este modelo inteligente, tenemos este sueño grande y audaz, que es resolver el 40 % del problema de las niñas excluidas de la escuela en India en los próximos cinco años. (Aplausos) Y Uds. pensarán que es un poco...
You know, how am I even thinking about doing that, because India is not a small place, it's a huge country. It's a country of over a billion people. We have 650,000 villages. How is it that I'm standing here, saying that one small organization is going to solve a full 40 percent of the problem? And that's because we have a key insight. And that is, because of our entire approach, with data and with technology, that five percent of villages in India have 40 percent of the out-of-school girls. And this is a big, big piece of the puzzle. Which means, I don't have to work across the entire country. I have to work in those five percent of the villages, about 35,000 villages, to actually be able to solve a large piece of the problem. And that's really key, because these villages not only have high burden of out-of-school girls, but also a lot of related indicators, right, like malnutrition, stunting, poverty, infant mortality,
Ya saben, como puedo pensar en hacer eso, porque India no es pequeña, es un país enorme, con más de 1000 millones de personas. Tenemos 650 000 pueblos. ¿Cómo puedo estar aquí diciendo que una organización pequeña va a resolver el 40 % del problema? Es porque tenemos una percepción clave, que es que debido a nuestro enfoque con sus datos y su tecnología el 5 % de los pueblos en India tienen un 40 % de niñas excluidas de la escuela. Y esta es una pieza grande del rompecabezas. Lo que significa que no tengo que trabajar en todo el país. Tengo que trabajar en ese 5 % de los pueblos, unos 35 000, para poder resolver una gran parte del problema. Y esa es la clave, porque estos pueblos no solo tienen la gran carga de las niñas excluidas de la escuela, sino también muchos otros indicadores relacionados, como la malnutrición, el retraso en el crecimiento, la pobreza, la mortalidad infantil,
child marriage. So by working and focusing here, you can actually create a large multiplier effect across all of these indicators. And it would mean that we would be able to bring back 1.6 million girls back into school. (Applause) I have to say, I have been doing this for over a decade, and I have never met a girl who said to me, you know, "I want to stay at home," "I want to graze the cattle," "I want to look after the siblings," "I want to be a child bride." Every single girl I meet wants to go to school. And that's what we really want to do. We want to be able to fulfill those 1.6 million dreams. And it doesn't take much. To find and enroll a girl with our model is about 20 dollars. To make sure that she is learning and providing a learning program, it's another 40 dollars. But today is the time to do it. Because she is truly the biggest asset we have. I am Safeena Husain, and I educate girls. Thank you. (Applause)
el matrimonio infantil... Al trabajar y concentrarnos en esto, podemos realmente crear un efecto multiplicador en todos estos indicadores. Y esto implicaría que podríamos hacer regresar a la escuela 1,6 millones de niñas. (Aplausos) Debo decir que he estado haciendo esto durante más de una década, y nunca encontré a una niña que me dijera: "Quiero quedarme en casa; quiero cuidar del ganado; quiero encargarme de mis hermanos; quiero ser una niña novia". Cada una de las niñas que conocí quiere ir a la escuela. Y eso es lo que realmente queremos hacer. Queremos poder cumplir esos millones de sueños. Y eso no cuesta mucho. Con nuestro modelo, encontrar e inscribir a una niña cuesta unos USD 20. Para garantizar que aprende y brindarle un programa de aprendizaje son otros USD 40. Ahora es el momento de hacerlo. Porque ella es, realmente, el mayor recurso que tenemos. Soy Safeena Husain, y educo a las niñas. Gracias. (Aplausos)